A Guide to the Governor's Office, Lists of Inhabitants, 1782-1785
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor's Office, Lists of Inhabitants, 1782-1785
Library of Virginia
34894
2.6 cu. ft. (5 oversized boxes), (Also available on microfilm, Miscellaneous Reel 1263)
Virginia. Office of the Governor.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Biographical/Historical Information
Clerks of the county courts were responsible for collecting the lists from justices and transmitting them to the Governor. The exact disposition of the records after their transmittal to the Governor is unclear.
Scope and Content Information
Lists of inhabitants, dated 1782 to 1785, for thirty-nine (39) Virginia counties and the town of Williamsburg. Information found in the lists for 1782 and 1783 include the name of the head of the household, the number of white inhabitants, and the number of enslaved people. The lists for 1784 and 1785 include the heads of households, the number of whites, and the numbers of dwelling houses and "outhouses."
Lists for the following counties and their year(s) are included in the collection: Albemarle (1785), Amelia (1782-1785), Amherst (1783-1785), Bedford (1783), Charlotte (1782-1783), Chesterfield (1783), Cumberland (1782,1784), Essex (1783), Fairfax (1782, 1785), Fluvanna (1782), Frederick (1782), Gloucester (1783-1784), Greenbrier (1783), Greensville (1783), Halifax (1782, 1785), Hampshire (1782, 1784), Hanover (1782), Harrison (1785), Isle of Wight (1782), Lancaster (1783, 1785), Mecklenburg (1782), Middlesex (1783), Monongalia (1782), Nansemond (1783-1785), New Kent (1782, 1784), Norfolk (1782, 1784-1785), Northumberland (1782, 1784), Orange (1784-1785), Pittsylvania (1782, 1785), Powhatan (1783), Prince Edward (1783, 1785), Princess Anne (1783, 1785), Richmond (1784), Rockingham (1783), Shenandoah (1785), Southampton (1783, 1785), Stafford (1785), Surry (1782, 1784), Sussex (1782), and Warwick (1782, 1784). There is also a list for the town of Williamsburg for 1782.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by county and chonologically therein.
Contents List
- Lists of Inhabitants,, 1782-1785..
  - Albemarle 1785 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amelia 1782 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amelia 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amhurst 1783 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amhurst 1785 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bedford 1783 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charlotte 1782 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Charlotte 1783 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chesterfield 1783 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cumberland 1782 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cumberland 1784 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Essex 1783 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax 1782 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax 1785 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fluvanna 1785 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Frederick 1782 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gloucester 1783 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gloucester 1784 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Greenbrier 1783 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Greensville 1783 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Halifax 1782 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Halifax 1785 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hampshire 1782 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hampshire 1784 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hampshire 1784 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hanover 1782 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Harrison 1785 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Isle of Wight 1782 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lancaster 1783 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lancaster 1785 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mecklenburg 1782 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Middlesex 1783 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Monongalia 1782 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Nansemond 1783 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Nansemond 1784 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Nansemond 1785 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - New Kent 1782 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - New Kent 1784 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Norfolk 1782 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Norfolk 1784 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Norfolk 1785 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Northumberland 1782 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Northumberland 1784 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Orange 1784 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Orange 1785 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pittsylvania 1782 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pittsylvania 1785 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Powhatan 1783 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Prince Edward 1783 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Prince Edward 1785 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Princess Anne 1783 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Princess Anne 1785 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Richmond 1784 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rockingham 1783 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Shenandoah 1785 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Southampton 1783 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Southampton 1785 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stafford 1785 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Surry 1782 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Surry 1784 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Sussex 1782 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Warwick 1782 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Warwick 1784 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Williamsburg City 1782 (Box 5, Folder 12)